

FULL STACK DEVELOPER · DATA SCIENTIS

São Luís - MA - Brazil

□ (+55) 98 98234 1517 | ■ joorgemelo@gmail.com | ★ jorgimello.github.io | ᡚ jorgimello | 匝 joorgeribeeiro

"Choose a job you love, and you will never have to work a day in your life."

Summary.

Current Full Stack Developer at Westwing Brazil. I have worked for the past 6 years as a Full Stack Developer with special interest in backend challenges. The goal of my life is to keep learning new technologies and tools to create and enhance products to improve people's lives. My daily routine is to be an engineer in full time, thinking solutions to optimize workflows and make suggestions to contribute to people's work. Last but not least, always an open-source lover.

Work Experience _____

Westwing Brazil Brazil

FULL STACK DEVELOPER Sep. 2019 - PRESENT

- Development of a new e-commerce system to sell products and integrate it to the current one.
- Debugging all the services included in the system in order to analyse its flows.
- · Adapting and translating the project (originally German) to reflect Brazilian market.
- · The project is built with Docker, Memcached, RabbitMQ, Solr and Dynamo. Based on PHP, Javascript and MySQL.
- My team works in an agile environment, and we use Jira to define stories and sprints.

Equatorial Energia Group

DATA SCIENTIST Mar. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Automating routines, reports and dashboards with Power BI for the Legal Department.
- · Analysing data from internal databases to help attorneys at their decision making.
- Applying Machine Learning techniques (R-Script) to interpret customer behavior.
- Development of applications to improve Tax and Corporate Law workflows and persist their data for further analysis.

Senior Team Projects and Solutions

Brazil

Rrazil

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Jan. 2018 - Feb. 2019

- Development of web applications to the Maranhão Audit Court using Java, EJB, ZK Framework and PostgreSQL.
- Refactored an application called Segurança (Security) that manages employees' user accounts and provides access to internal systems, along with two other team members.
- Started the development of the Obra Legal (Legal Construction) that will be used by public entities to enter information regarding public constructions occurring under their jurisdiction.

Maranhão Audit Court

Brazil

INTERN Jul. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Development of tools to the Superior School of External Control (ESCEX) using Java, EJB, ZK Framework and PostgreSQL.
- My main developed project was called Sophia, application that manages certifications via enrollment and attendance, to automatically generate certificate when the course ends.
- Developed Single-page applications to provide course enrollment and certificate prior to Sophia's release.

NEO Architecture and Enterprise

Brazil

DEVELOPER

Jul. 2013 - Jul. 2015

- Was given the task to organize customer data in order to fill in required forms.
- Developed an app to persist this data to a database (data used to be kept on spreadsheets). The app was also able to fill all the required forms automatically to be sent to federal banks.

Education

UFMA (Federal University of Maranhão)

Brazil

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

• This major was mostly focused on Software Engineering and Machine Learning.

• Developed a facial emotion classifier as an undergraduate thesis (repo can be found in the Projects section).

Carroll University

Wisconsin - USA

Aug. 2015 - May. 2016

Mar. 2014 - Dec. 2018

- EXCHANGE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE
- · Spent two semesters at this institution taking classes such as Software Design and Artificial Intelligence.
- This exchange was determinant to improve my english written and oral skills.

OCTOBER 2, 2019 JORGE RIBEIRO · RÉSUMÉ



Heart Disease Classifier

PYTHON, PANDAS, SKLEARN, FLASK, ANGULAR

- Classification of heart disease based on symptoms and personal features. It uses a heart disease dataset from the UCI Machine Learning Repository.
- Its source code and description can be found at https://github.com/jorgimello/heart-disease-classifier.

Computer Science Planner

LARAVEL, BULMA, SQLITE

- This application helps Computer Science Students from UFMA in the selection of classes in each semester, in order to complete the required hours in less time.
- Source code and instructions: https://github.com/jorgimello/planejador-cp-ufma.

Meta learning applied to the Problem of Facial Expression Recognition

Python, TensorFlow, Neural Networks, Meta Learning

- Undergraduate thesis developed to become a Computer Scientist bachelor.
- · It uses Convolutional Neural Networks and three datasets to learn emotions from human faces.
- Source code and docs can be found at https://github.com/jorgimello/meta-learning-facial-expression-recognition.

Github Web Scraper

PYTHON, BEAUTIFULSOUP, REQUESTS, PIPENV

- Crawler that gather information about files and sizes of any public Github repository. It creates a tree of files and folders and provides information about percentage of lines of code and bytes.
- Its source code and description can be found at https://github.com/jorgimello/github-web-scraper.